The Paul S. Martin papers, 1910-2006 MS 442
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
The Paul S. Martin papers 1910-2006
Collection Number: MS 442
Paul S. Martin
This collection consists of professional correspondence, research files and publication files of paleoecologist and geoscientist Dr. Paul S. Martin, Emeritus Professor of Geosciences at the University of Arizona. Collection also includes material relating to Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory, where Dr. Martin worked and conducted research for more than 50 years. Completing the collection are nine scrapbooks of newspaper clippings about ecological, social and political issues collected by Paul S. Martin from 1951-1970.
16 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None.
Biographical Note
Paul Schultz Martin was born August 22, 1928 in Allentown, Pennsylvania. He received his B.A. in Zoology from Cornell University in Ithaca, New York, in 1951. He then earned a Master’s degree in Zoology in 1953, followed by a Ph.D. in Zoology in 1956, both from University of Michigan in Ann Arbor. His early career aspiration to focus on collecting and studying plant and fossil specimens from tropical rainforests was cut short when he contracted polio at age 23 while in Mexico. After receiving his Ph.D., he conducted postdoctoral research in Biogeography at Yale University from 1955-1956 and then at Université de Montreal from 1956-1957. In 1957, he moved to Tucson to accept a position as a Research Associate with University of Arizona’s Geochronology Laboratories, thus beginning his long association with Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory. He was named Assistant Professor in 1961 and Associate Professor in 1962. He held the position of Professor in the Department of Geosciences from 1968 until 1989 when he was named Emeritus Professor. He remained an active researcher and vital part of the Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory for more than 50 years.
Dr. Martin is well-known as a primary developer and leading expert on the subject of prehistoric overkill, a pattern of global extinction over the last 40,000 years which coincided with human colonization spreading out of Africa and Asia. His theories have been the subject of much debate since the 1960’s and have helped rejuvenate interest in the study of prehistoric extinctions. His interest in the extinction chronology of late Pleistocene large animals has taken him to fossil sites all around the world including Chile, New Zealand and Australia. This fossil research led him to develop extinction models based on human activity as the main cause of the rapid extinctions of large animals such as the mammoth, mastodon and giant ground sloth. In addition, Dr. Martin conducted research about Pleistocene biotic changes in arid regions. He studied the biogeography of eastern Mexico, the Pleistocene fossil pollen record of Arizona, and the ability of fossil packrat middens to reveal important information about climatic changes. Dr. Martin is the author of numerous books and articles, including The Last 10,000 Years: A Fossil Pollen Study of the American Southwest, Pleistocene Extinctions: The Search for a Cause, and Twilight of the Mammoths. Before his retirement, he was also a highly regarded professor of Quaternary Biogeography for more than 30 years, well known for his gentle nature, memorable quotes, and enthusiasm for facilitating discovery and learning. His research gave him a unique, long range perspective on the mechanisms and impact of species extinction and environmental destruction. His dedication to ecological and social issues is reflected in his involvement with various efforts to protect endangered flora and fauna of the Southwest from potential human destruction.
This Collections is arranged into six series
Series I: Correspondence 1975-1990]
Series II: Publication Files 1951-2006
Series III: Research Files 1910-2000
Series IV: Newspaper Clippings 1959-2000
Series V: Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory 1960-2000
Series VI: Scrapbooks 1951-1970
Correspondence, research files, publication files, newspaper clippings and scrapbooks. The numerous boxes of correspondence files contain letters both written by and received by Dr. Martin during of his professional career (principally covers the years 1975-1990). This material includes correspondence with various scientists, researchers, publishers, students and others. The correspondence files are arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent. The first subseries of the research files consist of varied material gathered in the course of scientific and professional research. This subseries also contains copies of Dr. Martin’s National Science Foundation grant proposals, data on Southwestern fauna, efforts to stop the controversial construction of a telescope on Mount Graham, as well as other articles and newspaper clippings about varied topics. The second subseries of the research files contains records detailing data collected by Dr. Martin after the spraying of Agent Orange on the town of Globe, Arizona in 1969. The publication files contain copies of articles written by Dr. Martin over the course of his career, spanning from 1951-2006. Also included is correspondence to and from Dr. Martin regarding his published books and articles. The publication files also contain copies of reviews of Dr. Martin’s published works from various sources. The next series compiles newspaper clippings written about Dr. Paul S. Martin and his research during the years 1959-2000. The following series focuses on the Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory. This series contains correspondence related to activities at the Desert Lab, as well as fundraising materials, staff bibliographies and library information. Blueprints, planning and policy documents and research files are also included. Materials about flora and fauna of Tumamoc Hill are also present. Articles and photographs describing the history of Tumamoc Hill Desert Lab form another part of this series. Lastly, the various threats to the lab and its continued operation from the 1960’s through the early 2000’s are detailed through collected newspaper clippings. The final series of the collection consists of nine scrapbooks of newspaper clippings collected by Dr. Martin from 1951-1970 which detail political, social and ecological issues of the times.
Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution records(AZ 356), 1903-1938, Special Collections, University of Arizona Library.
Martin, Paul S. (Paul Schultz), (1928-.; Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution.; Botanical laboratories—Arizona—Tucson—History; Evolutionary paleoecology.; Desert ecology—Sonoran desert.; Globe (Ariz.) - History.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1975-1990
  This series is arranged alphabetically by last name of the correspondent.
  - Correspondence--A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--A (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--A (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--Agenbroad, Larry (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--Australia (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--B (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--Barlow, Connie (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--Betancourt, Julio (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--C (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--C (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--C (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--C (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--C (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--C (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--D (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--D (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--D (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--D (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--D (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--D (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Davis, George (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--Diamond, Jared (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--Dickinson, William (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--E (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--E (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--E (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--Euler, Robert (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence--F (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--F (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--F (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--F (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--Fisher, Donald (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Francis, Kevin (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--G (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--Gentry, Howard S (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Goldberg, Deborah (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--Grayson, Deborah (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--H (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--H (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--H (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--H (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--H (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--H (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--H (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--Hope, Jeannette (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--I (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Igarashi, Kyohei (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--J (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--J (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--Jansen, Daniel (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--Judge, W. James (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--K (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--K (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--K (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--K (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--K (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--K (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Kay, Charles (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--L (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--L (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--L (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--L (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--L (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--Long, Austin (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--Lagiglia, Humberto (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--Mc (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--Mc (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Mc (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--McCullough, Ed (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--McCullough, Ed (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--McDonald, Greg (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--M (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--MacPhee, Ross (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--Meadowcroft Rockshelter (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--Mehringer, Pete (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--Mosimann, James (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--Mosimann, James (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--O (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--O (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--O (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--P (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--P (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Q (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--R (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--R (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--R (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--R (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--Ray, Clayton (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--S (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--Sanders, Andrew (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--Sher, Andrei (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--Smiley, Terah (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--Spellenburg, Richard (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--Spellenburg, Richard (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--Stafford, Thomas (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--Steadman, David (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence--Stuart, Anthony (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--Stuart, Anthony (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--T (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--T (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--T (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--T (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--U (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--V (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence--W (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--W (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--W (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--W (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--W (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--W (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--X, Y, Z (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Series II: Publication Files
  This series consists of Dr. Paul S. Martin’s published works and related materials. The first part of this series containing published articles is arranged chronologically. The remaining files of correspondence and reviews are arranged alphabetically by the title of the published work to which the material refers.
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1951-1959 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1960-1964 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1968-1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1981-1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1987-1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Publication Files--Articles, 2000-2006 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Publication Files--Articles, Undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Publication Files--Articles, Undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Gentry’s Rio Mayo Plants (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Paleolithic Players on the American Stage (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Pleistocene Extinctions: The Search for a Cause (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Quaternary Extinctions: A Prehistoric Revolution (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Quaternary Extinctions: A Prehistoric Revolution (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Quaternary Extinctions: A Prehistoric Revolution (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Twilight of the Mammoths: Ice Age Extinctions and the Rewilding of America (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Publication Files--Correspondence--Twilight of the Mammoths: Ice Age Extinctions and the Rewilding of America (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Publication Files--Resumes--Reports and Conferences America (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Publication Files--Reviews--Gentry’s Rio Mayo Plants, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Publication Files--Reviews--The Last 10,000 Years: A Fossil Pollen Study of the American Southwest, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Publication Files--Reviews--Packrat Middens: The Last 40,000 Years of Biotic Change, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Publication Files--Reviews--Pleistocene Extinctions: The Search for a Cause, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Publication Files--Reviews--Quaternary Extinctions: A Prehistoric Revolution, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Publication Files--Reviews--Twilight of the Mammoths: Ice Age Extinctions and the Rewilding of America, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Publication Files--A Survey of Potential Natural Landmarks, Biotic Themes of the Mojave-Sonoran Desert Region, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Series III: Research Files
  Series note: This series is arranged alphabetically in two subseries: Subseries 1: General files and Subseries 2: Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona, 1969
  - Subseries 1: General files, 1910-2000
    - Research Files--Accelerator for Radioisotope Analysis (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Research Files--Australia (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Research Files--“Changes in Frost Frequency and Desert Vegetation Assemblages in Grand Canyon, Arizona” by Robert H. Webb & Janice E. Bowers (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Research Files--D’Autremont, Hugh (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Research Files--Evolution of Terpenes (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Research Files--“Govenia in Mexico” by E.W. Greenwood, (1981) (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Research Files--Grant proposals, 1970-1975 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Research Files--Grant proposals, 1975-1979 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Research Files--Grant proposals, 1980-1985 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Research Files--Grant proposals (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Research Files--“Grazing Ranges of Arizona” by J.J. Thornber(1910) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Research Files--Mammoth dates (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Research Files--Marmota bones, Palomas Cave, New Mexico (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Research Files--Mastodons (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Research Files--Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Research Files--Mount Graham (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Research Files--Mount Graham (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Research Files--Mount Graham (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Research Files--Newspaper clippings (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Research Files--Page Ranch (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Research Files--Research Ranch/Audubon Appleton-Whittel Research Ranch (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Research Files--Research Ranch/Audubon Appleton-Whittel Research Ranch (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Research Files--Santa Rita Research Station (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Research Files--Santa Rita Research Station (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Research Files--Santa Rita Research Station (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Research Files--Sierra de Alamos, Sonora, Mexico (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Research Files--Southwestern flora and fauna (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Research Files--Van Devender, Thomas (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Research Files--Plant List (1) (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Research Files--Plant List (2) (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Research Files--Plant List (3) (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Research Files--Plant List (4) (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 2: Agent Orange Spray, Globe, Arizona, 1969
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Correspondence, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Correspondence, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Correspondence, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Herbicide Information, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Herbicide Reports, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Laboratory Reports, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--McKusick, Robert, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Miscellaneous and notes, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Miscellaneous and notes, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires--Crestwood, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires--Crestwood, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires--Crestwood, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires--Ice House Canyon, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires--Kellver Canyon, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires--Russel Gulch, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Questionnaires--Six Shooters, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Reports of investigations, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Shoecraft, Willard and Billie, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Agent Orange spray, Globe, Arizona,--Shoecraft et al. vs. Dow Chemical, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Newspaper Clippings,1959-2000
  Series note: These collected articles focus on the career and research of Dr. Paul S. Martin. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1959-1964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1965-1969 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1970-1974 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1985-1987 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings1990-1993 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Series V: Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory,1960-2000
  Series note: This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Bibliography lists of Desert Lab Researchers (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Bibliography lists of Desert Lab Researchers (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Blueprints and maps (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Events (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Faculty, Researchers and Staff (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Fauna (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Flora (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Flora (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Flora--Tumamoca macdouglaii (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Fundraising correspondence (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Fundraising correspondence (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Fundraising correspondence (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Fundraising materials (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Fundraising materials (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Fundraising materials (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --History (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --History (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Library (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Negatives (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Newspaper clippings (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Newspaper clippings (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Photographs (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Photographs (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Planning and policy (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Planning and policy (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Tumamoc Hill Desert Laboratory --Planning and policy (Box 25, Folder 8)